<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 
 <title>LimitlessChannels</title>
 <link href="http://limitlesschannels.com/feed/" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://limitlesschannels.com/"/>
 <updated>2012-02-22T23:15:21-08:00</updated>
 <id>http://limitlesschannels.com/</id>
 <author>
   <name>LimitlessChannels</name>
   <email>mail@limitlesschannels.com</email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Site Migration</title>
   <link href="http://limitlesschannels.com/site/2012/02/19/Site-Migration.html"/>
   <updated>2012-02-19T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>http://limitlesschannels.com/site/2012/02/19/Site-Migration</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Why&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In moving over my site from Squarespace, a well-known and excellent WYSIWYG site editor and host, I wanted to try something different.  Until I am producing content with the quality to surpass whatever medium its presented on, I don't really get the point in hosting a site in which I have no understanding of the innards.  In other words, right now I want an online repository for what I'm interested in and a presence for myself.  Until the information is abundant enough to stand on its own, I will consider the medium to be the message, and this medium is the site coding, et al. Oh, it's also way cheaper.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;How&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This site was made possible by many great people who live public online, letting me check out code and their excellent blogposts describing the process. Some of those include &lt;a href='http://recursive-design.com/blog/2010/10/12/static-blogging-the-jekyll-way/' target='_blank'&gt;this solid blogpost&lt;/a&gt; on Recursive Design, &lt;a href='http://bilalh.github.com' target='_blank'&gt;Bilal Syed Hussain&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href='http://gwern.net' target='_blank'&gt;gwern&lt;/a&gt;. Other sources include gwern's excellent &lt;a href='http://gwern.net/about' target='_blank'&gt;About Page&lt;/a&gt;, and a little bit of last minute post-receive Git hooks fixed by &lt;a href='http://twitter.com/reidab' target='_blank'&gt;@Reidab&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The source for my site is hosted over on &lt;a href='http://github.com' target='_blank'&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;.  I edit the source files locally, push them to my server and to Github with git, and then on the serverside Jekyll builds the static content and voila.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Rather than start from complete scratch I looked for an ultraminimal html/css pair to build off and discovered the beautiful and clean templates of &lt;a href='http://andreasviklund.com'&gt;Andreas Viklun.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hosting is provided by &lt;a href='http://nearlyfreespeech.net'&gt;NearlyFreeSpeech.net&lt;/a&gt;(Recommended by gwern).  It's early but NFSN seems great so far.  It is a pay-as-you-go provider, which makes it a very affordable venture and transition from the ~$20 a month I was paying at Squarespace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rather than start from complete scratch I looked for an ultraminimal html/css pair to build off and discovered the beautiful and clean templates of Andrea Viklun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hosting is provided by NearlyFreeSpeech.net (Recommended by Gwern). It&amp;#8217;s early but NFSN seems great so far. It is a pay-as-you-go provider, which makes it a very affordable venture and transition from the ~$20 a month I was paying at Squarespace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It looks like I finally got my new blog up and running, yay!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The basic site is now running hosted at the awesome (and cheap) hosting provider NearlyFreeSpeech.net. The static content is being generated with Jekyll and pushed to the server via Git. I had next to no knowledge of version control systems and only a vague understanding of the precise difference between static and dynamic content websites prior. In other words, I have done very little webdev outside of basic HTML/CSS crafting. Therefore moving from an overly expensive and incredibly simple WYSIWYG generator and host like squarespace to something barebones was an interesting and important journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once I get everything finished I will be migrating over all my posts, adding RSS, figuring out how to throw up a GoogleAnalytics engine, and hopefully getting comments up with Disqus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am sure plenty is broken and since I wrote this all for scratch more or less in vi (like an idiot who thinks its important to jump without a net) let me know what I need to fix and if you are feeling up for it pop open the source and tell me where I dropped a close bracket or whatever.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Journal Entry for 19feb2012</title>
   <link href="http://limitlesschannels.com/journal/2012/02/19/Journal-Entry-for-19feb2012.html"/>
   <updated>2012-02-19T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>http://limitlesschannels.com/journal/2012/02/19/Journal-Entry-for-19feb2012</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This day was a musical one. I went with a friend to the Oregon Symphony to see one of (allegedly) the world&amp;#8217;s best pianists, Jeffrey Kahane, performing Mozart&amp;#8217;s Concerto No. 25 along with a few other pieces. I personally preferred Cockaigne&amp;#8217;s &amp;#8220;In London Town&amp;#8221; due to my preference for dynamics over&amp;#8230; whatever the alternative is. It is a queer feeling to hear what is very often considered the greatest music to ever exist. Perhaps its &amp;#8220;perfection&amp;#8221; lulls me enough to not recognize the brilliance of the piece, but as I said, the dynamics of such craziness as Cockaigne (easy to remember as pronunciation follows the nose-candy namesake) seem more memorable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I have gone to other &amp;#8220;high society&amp;#8221; performance things before, mostly musicals and a few dance pieces, this was my first real symphony. It is an interesting environment of largely older people and a glimpse into an experience I rarely get access to. I told my companion after how I was glad I am friends with interests so different from my own because I would be hardpressed to commit to going to the symphony without someone else&amp;#8217;s support. I doubt I will go again unless it there is some overwhelming performance or my opinion changes, but the epicness of such an experience was a joy to experience at least once.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the symphony we changed it up and headed to Karaoke. It was a bit less energetic than last time I went to the same bar but still fun. The selection was a bit varied but if I had to put the night in a genre it was more drama than the comedic karaoke sessions I prefer. I sung Rick Astley&amp;#8217;s &amp;#8220;Never Gonna Give you up&amp;#8221; and my friend and I sung &amp;#8220;The Rainbow Connection.&amp;#8221; It would appear that success in karaoke comes mostly from familiarity with the material and barely at all with actual singing skill, of which I have little.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>On Posting</title>
   <link href="http://limitlesschannels.com/main/2012/02/15/on-posting.html"/>
   <updated>2012-02-15T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>http://limitlesschannels.com/main/2012/02/15/on-posting</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I apologize for completely falling off the map. I&amp;#8217;ve been nuts busy with school (this is my last semester at my university) and am constantly struggling with my attempt to appreciate higher education while being completely burnt out and wanting to get out. Meanwhile, I have acquired Skyrim and that thing has monopolized all my time since I have a video game problem that I will occasionally lapse back into. Between those two things I haven&amp;#8217;t been present much at all in the webosphere, especially the blogsphere but still only rare twitter/g+/facebook/etc posts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have just recommitted to keeping up my online presence and I hope to keep it going pretty soon again. Sorry for the low-flow, I&amp;#8217;m working on fixing that up. Meanwhile, Squarespace is damn expensive. I will be moving my blog as soon as I am able as well and given my limited past commitment to WebDev, that may be quick or it may take a painfully long time to transition (probably the latter).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cheers.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Mimic Method - Language Learning System</title>
   <link href="http://limitlesschannels.com/language/2012/01/17/mimic-method-language-learning-system.html"/>
   <updated>2012-01-17T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>http://limitlesschannels.com/language/2012/01/17/mimic-method-language-learning-system</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;While reading Metafilter I stumbled on a new language learning system developed by Idahosa Ness called the Mimic Method. In the perpetual attempt to perfect pronunciation and accent acquisition, this method focuses on mimicry to achieve accurate pronunciation and reproduction. It is actually not far off from the method children use during language acquisition (see fixed forms and derived forms in child speech). It&amp;#8217;s in &lt;a href='http://www.mimicmethod.com/about.html' target='_blank'&gt;beta right now, but feel free to sign up&lt;/a&gt;. Once I get in I&amp;#8217;ll report back with some tidbits and first impressions.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Gesture-Encoded Memory</title>
   <link href="http://limitlesschannels.com/neuroscience/2012/01/04/gesture-encoded-memory.html"/>
   <updated>2012-01-04T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>http://limitlesschannels.com/neuroscience/2012/01/04/gesture-encoded-memory</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Been reading about gesture-encoded memory a lot lately. &amp;nbsp;After noticing a recent 2009 paper by Kelly, McDevitt, &amp;amp; Esch on the subject (&lt;a href='http://www.tandfonline.com/doi/abs/10.1080/01690960802365567'&gt;HERE&lt;/a&gt;) I did a bit of research and rediscovered one of the more innovative applications of this through what is known as &lt;a href='http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/TPR_Storytelling'&gt;TPRS&lt;/a&gt;, that's Teaching Proficiency through Reading and Storytelling. &amp;nbsp;Having known someone who went through one of the programs briefly, I began to discuss it with them and they considered it quite effective. &amp;nbsp;I'll hopefully post a more detailed description in the next few days when I have time.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>How to Actually Change your Mind</title>
   <link href="http://limitlesschannels.com/neuroscience/2011/08/22/how-to-actually-change-your-mind.html"/>
   <updated>2011-08-22T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://limitlesschannels.com/neuroscience/2011/08/22/how-to-actually-change-your-mind</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A phenomenal collection of threads on LessWrong on &lt;a href='http://wiki.lesswrong.com/wiki/How_To_Actually_Change_Your_Mind' class='offsite-link-inline' target='_blank'&gt;how to actually change your mind&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;nbsp;Highlights include&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='http://lesswrong.com/lw/ur/crisis_of_faith/' target='_blank'&gt;Crisis of Faith&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;#religion #faith #rationality&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='http://lesswrong.com/lw/k5/cached_thoughts/' target='_blank'&gt;Cached Thoughts&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;#memory #neuroscience&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='http://lesswrong.com/lw/or/joy_in_the_merely_real/' target='_blank'&gt;Joy in the Merely Real&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='http://lesswrong.com/lw/jr/how_to_convince_me_that_2_2_3/' target='_blank'&gt;How to Convince me that 2 + 2 = 3&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;#rationality #empiricism&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Italy no longer able to afford Italian Language</title>
   <link href="http://limitlesschannels.com/language/2011/08/21/italy-no-longer-able-to-afford-italian-language.html"/>
   <updated>2011-08-21T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://limitlesschannels.com/language/2011/08/21/italy-no-longer-able-to-afford-italian-language</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Apparently the foremost institute for maintenance of the Italian language (think '&lt;em&gt;L'academie francaise&lt;/em&gt;' of Italy) can &lt;a href='http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/2011/aug/19/italian-language-under-threat-cuts' target='_blank'&gt;no longer sustainably afford to fund its own language&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;nbsp;The struggle between people who try and govern the language with an iron fist and economics has always been an interesting and arbitrary one. &amp;nbsp;Still, it is one that a shockingly large subset of people think is necessary and there are many languages around the world with such similar institutions (see Wikipedia's &lt;a href='http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_language_academies' target='_blank'&gt;List of Language Regulators&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>DARPA and IBM work on new 'Cognitive Computer'</title>
   <link href="http://limitlesschannels.com/neuroscience/2011/08/21/darpa-and-ibm-work-on-new-cognitive-computer.html"/>
   <updated>2011-08-21T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://limitlesschannels.com/neuroscience/2011/08/21/darpa-and-ibm-work-on-new-cognitive-computer</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Nature has an interview with a fellow involved in the new DARPA/IBM project on &lt;a href='http://www.nature.com/news/2011/110818/full/news.2011.486.html' target='_blank'&gt;building a chip that emulated a cognitive network&lt;/a&gt; by emulating neuron interactions between transistors and RAM (as opposed to the traditional chip which uses a CENTRAL processing unit as the central executive. &amp;nbsp;Think network model and not monolithic architecture.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Learn to Speak Like a Woman</title>
   <link href="http://limitlesschannels.com/language/2011/08/19/learn-to-speak-like-a-woman.html"/>
   <updated>2011-08-19T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://limitlesschannels.com/language/2011/08/19/learn-to-speak-like-a-woman</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;a piece over on Wonderland about the transgender switch and &lt;a href='http://blogs.plos.org/wonderland/2011/08/17/learning-to-speak-like-a-woman/' target='_blank'&gt;learning to speak like a woman&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;nbsp;The article has some great information on the therapy process (see excerpt below) and a brief interview on the subject.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;From the article:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I watched from an observation room as a clinician sat at a computer that monitors pitch and asked Caroline to hold certain vowel sounds for as long as she could. To me, her voice sounded quite feminine, but Caroline was tough on herself: After one assessment, she guessed that her pitch was 145. (Anything between 145 and 165 is considered gender neutral.) The clinician reassured her: The real number was 198, very close to the average range of feminine pitch of 210-220. Caroline then read a passage selected to contain all the sounds in the English language. This time, her average pitch was 177, just above gender neutral. &amp;ldquo;I still can&amp;rsquo;t find my voice,&amp;rdquo; says Caroline, disappointed. She also had work to do on her laugh, her cough, and her sneeze.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>A Necessary Vanity - Perspectives on Plastic Surgery in Brazil</title>
   <link href="http://limitlesschannels.com/neuroscience/2011/08/18/a-necessary-vanity-perspectives-on-plastic-surgery-in-brazil.html"/>
   <updated>2011-08-18T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://limitlesschannels.com/neuroscience/2011/08/18/a-necessary-vanity-perspectives-on-plastic-surgery-in-brazil</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The always great Mind Hacks recently posted a link to a NYT Opinion piece on the perspective Brazilians have on plastic surgery. &amp;nbsp;I observed this quite a bit when I was down in Brazil and it was fascinating. &amp;nbsp;I've been looking for a piece on this for some time, so &lt;a href='http://opinionator.blogs.nytimes.com/2011/08/13/a-necessary-vanity/' target='_blank'&gt;here it is&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;From the article:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After seeing the parade, I began to notice that Rio&amp;rsquo;s plastic surgery clinics were almost as numerous as beauty parlors (and there are a lot of those).&amp;nbsp; Newsstands sold magazines with titles like&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href='http://www.plasticaebeleza.com.br/'&gt;Pl&amp;aacute;stica &amp;amp; Beauty&lt;/a&gt;, next to Marie Claire.&amp;nbsp; I assumed that the popularity of cosmetic surgery in a developing nation was one more example of Brazil&amp;rsquo;s gaping inequalities.&amp;nbsp; But Pitanguy had long maintained that plastic surgery was not only for the rich: &amp;ldquo;The poor have the right to be beautiful, too,&amp;rdquo; he has said.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Psychoanalysis and plastic surgery, both once maverick medical specialties, overlapped closely in their historical development.&amp;nbsp; While the &amp;ldquo;talking cure&amp;rdquo; treated bodily complaints via the mind, plastic surgery healed mental suffering via the body.&amp;nbsp; Historian Sander Gilman called plastic surgery &amp;ldquo;psychoanalysis in reverse.&amp;rdquo;&amp;nbsp; In Brazil, as in Argentina, psychoanalysis enjoyed extraordinary popularity among wealthier Brazilians. But many veterans of Freudian or Lacananian therapy have supplemented or supplanted it with pl&amp;aacute;stica. For the patients at public hospitals, psychoanalysis had never been &amp;ldquo;an option,&amp;rdquo; a psychologist who worked in Pitanguy&amp;rsquo;s clinic told me. Echoing the words of the mischievous Carnival designer, she explained, &amp;ldquo;The poor prefer surgery.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Why you don't care about the deaths of millions of people</title>
   <link href="http://limitlesschannels.com/neuroscience/2011/08/16/why-you-dont-care-about-the-death-of-millions-of-people.html"/>
   <updated>2011-08-16T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://limitlesschannels.com/neuroscience/2011/08/16/why-you-dont-care-about-the-death-of-millions-of-people</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In [a] study people were paid to participate in an unrelated psychological quiz, and on the way out they were given the opportunity to donate up to $5.00 of their earnings to Save The Children. They were given three options:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They could donate to help Rokia, a 7 year-old Malian girl. The subjects were shown a picture of Rokia. They were willing to give $2.25.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They could donate to help the hundreds of thousands of children in eastern Africa who were starving. They were willing to give only $1.15.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The third option was to help Rokia specifically, but along with this request subjects were also given the statistics about the other starving east African kids. The same people who were willing to give $2.25 when it was just for Rokia, were only willing to give $1.40 when the request to help Rokia included information about the larger statistics!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='http://www.psychologytoday.com/blog/how-risky-is-it-really/201108/statistical-numbing-why-millions-can-die-and-we-don-t-care' class='offsite-link-inline' target='_blank'&gt;Psychology Today&lt;/a&gt; via&amp;nbsp;Lifehacker&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div /&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Coldplay fans least likely to have sex on first date, Nirvana fans most likely</title>
   <link href="http://limitlesschannels.com/statistics/2011/08/16/coldplay-fans-least-likely-to-have-sex.html"/>
   <updated>2011-08-16T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://limitlesschannels.com/statistics/2011/08/16/coldplay-fans-least-likely-to-have-sex</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Some people over on Tastebuds.fm compiled some data on correlations between favorite bands and likeliness of having sex on first date. &amp;nbsp;Using data from Last.fm's top 20 artists, &lt;a href='http://blog.tastebuds.fm/coldplay-fans-least-likely-to-have-sex-on-first-date/' target='_blank'&gt;Coldplay fans least likely, Nirvana fans most likely&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>iBoyfriend - Learning English in the arms of virtual boyfriends</title>
   <link href="http://limitlesschannels.com/language/2011/08/15/iboyfriend-learn-english-in-the-arms-of-virtual-boyfriends.html"/>
   <updated>2011-08-15T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://limitlesschannels.com/language/2011/08/15/iboyfriend-learn-english-in-the-arms-of-virtual-boyfriends</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Amazing new Japanese iPhone app for learning English:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This application, as you might have guessed, is a novel new twist on foreign language &amp;lsquo;edutainment&amp;rsquo;. Consumers begin a virtual relationship with one of three characters, and as their romantic love story unfolds, English conversational ability is apparently enhanced! Wow!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;via &lt;a href='http://www.languageonthemove.com/language-learning-gender-identity/iboyfriend' class='offsite-link-inline' target='_blank'&gt;Language on the Move&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Favorite Unromantic Theories of Love and Friendship Limits</title>
   <link href="http://limitlesschannels.com/neuroscience/2011/08/13/favorite-unromantic-theories-of-love-and-friendship-limits.html"/>
   <updated>2011-08-13T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://limitlesschannels.com/neuroscience/2011/08/13/favorite-unromantic-theories-of-love-and-friendship-limits</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Two nice links for today on human dynamics: theories of love and the dunbar number.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style='font-size: 110%;'&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Favorite unromantic theories of love&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1) The Love Triangle&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2) The Color Wheel&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3) The Mere Exposure Effect (my personal favorite)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4) The Clone Attraction&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5) The Commitment Equation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Via&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href='http://psych-your-mind.blogspot.com/2011/08/my-favorite-unromantic-theories-of-love.html' class='offsite-link-inline' target='_blank'&gt;Psych Your Mind&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style='font-size: 110%;'&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Is there a limit on how many friends you can have?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...Microblogging and mobile devices appear to augment human social capabilities, which raises the question whether they remove cognitive or biological constraints on human communication.&lt;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;In this paper we analyze a dataset of Twitter conversations collected across six months involving 1.7 million individuals and test the theoretical cognitive limit on the number of stable social relationships known as Dunbar's number. We find that the data are in agreement with Dunbar's result; users can entertain a maximum of 100&amp;ndash;200 stable relationships.&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;Thus, the &amp;lsquo;economy of attention&amp;rsquo; is limited in the online world by cognitive and biological constraints as predicted by Dunbar's theory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Via&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href='http://t.co/ydrsUjK' class='offsite-link-inline' target='_blank'&gt;Barking Up the Wrong Tree&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Android N-Back App Comparison</title>
   <link href="http://limitlesschannels.com/main/2011/08/10/android-n-back-app-comparison.html"/>
   <updated>2011-08-10T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://limitlesschannels.com/main/2011/08/10/android-n-back-app-comparison</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p style='text-align: center;'&gt;&lt;em style='font-size: 90%;'&gt;My previous article describes N-Back a bit better for those who missed it or are interested: &lt;a href='http://bit.ly/r6g9r7' target='_blank'&gt;What Exactly is N-Back?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bit of Background&lt;/strong&gt;: Now that I've finally started putting in daily N-Back sessions and just like the rest of my life, I've been slowly converting everything to mobile so I can handle all my tasks away from a computer. &amp;nbsp;Best case scenario I find a universally-compatible program with a desktop and mobile component. &amp;nbsp;While that part is still severely lacking (nothing here has a desktop equivalent) there are some rough hacks involving dropbox that I have been working on. &amp;nbsp;Until I perfect that script anyway, I will stick entirely to my Android phone. &amp;nbsp;Which app is the best? &amp;nbsp;Well as of August 10th, I've tried all the dedicated ones and even the paid ones. So, on to the comparison.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are currently 6 main candidates in the app market: Quazar's &lt;a href='https://market.android.com/details?id=quazar.BrainNBack&amp;amp;feature=search_result' target='_blank'&gt;Brain N Back&lt;/a&gt;, Nguyen's &lt;a href='https://market.android.com/details?id=phuc.entertainment.dualnback&amp;amp;feature=search_result' target='_blank'&gt;Brain N-Back&lt;/a&gt;, Polytech's &lt;a href='https://market.android.com/details?id=com.Projet4A.DualNBack&amp;amp;feature=search_result' target='_blank'&gt;DualNBack&lt;/a&gt;, and Piotr's &lt;a href='https://market.android.com/details?id=cz.wie.p.nback&amp;amp;feature=search_result' target='_blank'&gt;N-Back&lt;/a&gt;.  Given the complete lack of creative naming this review might get absurdly confusing, so I'll try and use the author's name for these.  Oh, also there is &lt;a href='https://market.android.com/details?id=waterdev.NBack&amp;amp;feature=search_result' target='_blank'&gt;Waterdev's NBack&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href='https://market.android.com/details?id=appinventor.ai_viana_octavio.IQ_Boost_free&amp;amp;feature=search_result' target='_blank'&gt;IQBoost&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span style='text-decoration: line-through;'&gt;but since I'm a cheap bastard right now, I haven't quite gone out and bought this these&lt;/span&gt; since I wasn't super satisfied with all the other offerings, I decided to try out these two, as well.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style='padding-left: 30px;'&gt;&lt;span style='font-size: 90%;'&gt;&lt;em&gt;A note on feedback: I think the feedback feature can be detrimental to the exercise since it is too easy to get caught up mid-task and analyze one's correct or incorrect move, affecting the spontanaeity and focus of the exercise. Feedback can be useful occasionally for &quot;calibrating&quot; oneself to the new N- turn variable, but otherwise I believe should be avoided, hence I do not tend to mention it as a feature here.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style='text-decoration: underline;'&gt;Quazar's Brain N Back&lt;strong&gt;(free)&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Quazar's app is about as bare-bones as you can get, it's for doing N-Backs and that's about it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://market.android.com/details?id=quazar.BrainNBack&amp;amp;feature=search_result' target='_blank'&gt;&lt;img src='/images/nback/quazar.jpg' alt='' style='width: 150px;' /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style='white-space: pre;'&gt; &lt;/span&gt;+ Choice of Single, Dual, or Triple N-Back&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style='white-space: pre;'&gt; &lt;/span&gt;- No statistics&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style='white-space: pre;'&gt; &lt;/span&gt;- No resuming&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style='white-space: pre;'&gt; &lt;/span&gt;- Not super aesthetically pleasing&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style='white-space: pre;'&gt; &lt;/span&gt;Rating:&lt;span style='white-space: pre;'&gt; &lt;/span&gt;4 / 10&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style='text-decoration: underline;'&gt;Nguyen's Brain N-Back&lt;strong&gt; (free or donated)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style='text-decoration: underline;'&gt;&lt;span style='text-decoration: underline;'&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Solid app with all the core features (statistics and variable stimulus; i.e. position, color, and shape) with no major issues in terms of stability.  After a week of use it didn't crash once.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style='white-space: pre;'&gt;&lt;span class='full-image-float-left ssNonEditable'&gt;&lt;a href='https://market.android.com/details?id=phuc.entertainment.dualnback&amp;amp;feature=search_result' target='_blank'&gt;&lt;img src='/images/nback/Nguyen.png' alt='' style='width: 150px;' /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style='white-space: pre;'&gt; &lt;/span&gt;+ Stable and Pretty&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style='white-space: pre;'&gt; &lt;/span&gt;+ Both daily and overrall statistics&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style='white-space: pre;'&gt; &lt;/span&gt;- &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Detailed&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; daily statistics only, not overrall statistics or ability to reference old days individually&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style='white-space: pre;' /&gt;- Fewer settings; i.e. No session limit per day&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;- Ads. &amp;nbsp;But removable with premium version&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style='white-space: pre;'&gt; &lt;/span&gt;Rating:&lt;span style='white-space: pre;'&gt; &lt;/span&gt;8 / 10&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;** Interesting feature note: Audio stimulus can be changed from letters to piano notes!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style='text-decoration: underline;'&gt;Polytech Marseille's DualNBack (free):&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; As the name states, this is for purely &lt;em&gt;Dual&lt;/em&gt; N-Back.  That being said, there's still N- adjustment and a clean interface for getting it done.  Unfortunately, the recorded audio-letter stimulus is so horrible I can't legitimately tell if it is French or English; I only say French due to the app's name.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class='full-image-float-left ssNonEditable'&gt;&lt;a href='https://market.android.com/details?id=com.Projet4A.DualNBack&amp;amp;feature=search_result' target='_blank'&gt;&lt;img src='/images/nback/polytechmarseille.png' alt='' style='width: 150px;' /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; + Clean Interface&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; + Easy N- adjustment (cool little side buttons)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; - Virtually no adjustment otherwise (stimulus, sessions, orientation, etc.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; - No statistics&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; Rating: 3 / 10&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style='text-decoration: underline;'&gt;Piotr's N-Back (free):&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This one was interesting, given the less then detailed explanation in the market I assumed it to be fairly minimal like Quazar's but Piotr's actually has some of the best settings of any of the apps. In my brief testing it was stable, however the audio was not very clear and the control scheme was a mess on my 4.3&quot; screen. One review said it was designed for the Nexus One (4&quot; screen, so perhaps that is the issue).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span class='full-image-float-left ssNonEditable'&gt;&lt;a href='https://market.android.com/details?id=cz.wie.p.nback&amp;amp;feature=search_result' target='_blank'&gt;&lt;img src='/images/nback/Piotr.png' alt='' style='width: 150px;' /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;+ Most extensive feature set I've seen so far; number of sessions, % to advance, starting N-, feedback&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;+ Variety of stimulus&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;- Somewhat confusing controls&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; - Unpolished interface&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; - Can't tell if the statistics are actually working...&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rating: 7 / 10&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style='text-decoration: underline;'&gt;Waterdev's NBack ($1.50):&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; For one of the only current paid N-Back apps, I had high hopes for Waterdev and while it is indeed quite polished with more then the minimal options of other ones it still has a limited feature set. Feature-wise it may be a bit lacking but as stated for the aesthetically-inclined, this is the clear winner.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class='full-image-float-left ssNonEditable'&gt;&lt;img src='/images/nback/Waterdev.png' alt='' style='width: 150px;' /&gt;&lt;/span&gt; + Beautiful and Stable&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; + Ability to set different profiles&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; + Statistics (overall only)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; - Doesn't inhibit lockscreen, which may turn on mid-game and void current round.  This can be a real deal-breaker&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; - Limited feature set&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rating: 6 / 10&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style='text-decoration: underline;'&gt;IQ Boost (free or $1.00):&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here's the other paid N-back in the market, nearly brand new having been posted only two weeks ago. IQBoost is a iOS port that has finally made it to Android. The interface is well constructed with quality sound and graphics, yet it has only a few options for defining task.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class='full-image-float-left ssNonEditable'&gt;&lt;img src='/images/nback/IQBoost.png' alt='' style='width: 150px;' /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; + Variable stimulus; either sound, spatial, or both&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; - Only single or dual N-back possible&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; - Unique style. Audio stimulus uses farm animals rather than letters or numbers&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; + Allows for variable duration, which may or may not actually be useful&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; - Statistics?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;** Interesting feature note: IQ Boost also comes in a &quot;boys name version&quot; and &quot;girls name version.&quot; &amp;nbsp;No idea what that is and there's no description.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rating: 5 / 10&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style='text-decoration: underline;'&gt;The Winner:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Piotr's NBack clearly has the best feature set and options that I really want in an app, yet awkward layout (at least for my 4.3 screen) and while it has most of what I'm looking for, one other seems to bring it all together in the most packaged and balanced way, so without further ado:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nguyen's N-Back!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While there are a couple features still lacking, Nguyen's still had the greatest balance of features with the right amount of interface polish. While it still lacks some certain features, Nguyen appears to be a pretty great dev who responds to all requests, so I'll be submitting my desired features and we shall see if we can't make the best on so far a bit better. Meanwhile, if you feel like supporting him, there's a &lt;a href='https://market.android.com/details?id=phuc.entertainment.dualnbackpremium&amp;amp;feature=search_result' class='offsite-link-inline' target='_blank'&gt;&quot;premium&quot; ad-free version on the market&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I'm still not entirely satisfied with the apps available right now, so until I get a few more features or stability in each, I'll be sticking with Nguyen's.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Things I still want:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exporting&lt;/strong&gt; (if any did have this then I would have just posted my own N-Back daily sessions here in some nice data-aggregating fashion)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Better statistics&lt;/strong&gt;, that is the ability to review previous days in detail&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Session limits for the day&lt;/strong&gt;, i.e. stopping at 20 rather than infinite regression&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h2 id='comments'&gt;COMMENTS:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AUTHOR: Roman DATE: 10/15/2011 01:29:51 PM &lt;p&gt;Thanks for detailed review, saved hours of my life.&lt;br /&gt;I have 4&amp;quot; screen so will try best and second best app.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Why Non-rapid Eye Movement (NREM) sleep is important for memory</title>
   <link href="http://limitlesschannels.com/neuroscience/2011/08/09/why-non-rem-is-important-for-memory.html"/>
   <updated>2011-08-09T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://limitlesschannels.com/neuroscience/2011/08/09/why-non-rem-is-important-for-memory</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Born and colleagues (2007) had human subject learn card pair locations while smelling different odors simultaneously (the top left card paired with the scent of my feet, for example). When the researchers reintroduced those same smells during the subjects' slow wave sleep (my feet in the poor subject's face), memory for the card pair locations (top left card) tied to those smells (my feet) were enhanced at recall the next day. Also, through fMRI they saw reactivation of the hippocampus during slow wave sleep.&amp;nbsp;In an alternative study, they used transcranial magnetic stimulation to essentially boost slow oscillations during NREM sleep, which not only increased slow wave sleep and sleep spindles, but also enhanced declarative memory consolidation.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;From these findings they developed a model postulating that slow waves originating from the neocortex synced both hippocampal sharp waves and thalamocortical sleep spindles, resulting in primed cortical networks for long-term memory storage. &lt;strong&gt;The research team was the first to provide empirical support for a causal role of hippocampal memory reactivation for memory enhancement during sleep.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The key point I'm trying to emphasize here is that slow wave sleep and sleep spindle activity are essential for sleep dependent declarative memory consolidation.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='http://thequantumlobechronicles.blogspot.com/2011/08/why-non-rapid-eye-movement-nrem-sleep.html'&gt;V&lt;/a&gt;ia &lt;a href='http://thequantumlobechronicles.blogspot.com/2011/08/why-non-rapid-eye-movement-nrem-sleep.html' class='offsite-link-inline' target='_blank'&gt;QuantumLobeChronicles&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bonus:&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some more recent memory research: &lt;a href='http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/notrocketscience/2011/08/05/five-myths-about-memory-and-why-they-matter-in-court' class='offsite-link-inline' target='_blank'&gt;5 Myths about Memory&lt;/a&gt;, Click for the gallery.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>What Exactly is N-Back?</title>
   <link href="http://limitlesschannels.com/neuroscience/2011/08/09/what-exactly-is-nback.html"/>
   <updated>2011-08-09T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://limitlesschannels.com/neuroscience/2011/08/09/what-exactly-is-nback</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class='full-image-block ssNonEditable'&gt;&lt;img src='http://brainworkshop.sourceforge.net/session.png?__SQUARESPACE_CACHEVERSION=1312940352396' alt='' /&gt;&lt;span class='thumbnail-caption' style='width: 340px;'&gt;via Brainworkshop&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I've talked about N-Back quite a bit here and since it is currently the basis for my two month long cognitive training experiment I figured I should probably explain this a bit. &amp;nbsp;I gave a brief description previously &lt;a href='http://www.limitlesschannels.com/main/2011/8/2/life-update-blog-posts-and-cognitive-enhancement.html' target='_blank'&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; but it was more of a hand-off to an overly long and detailed post. &amp;nbsp;I will probably be talking about this quite a bit in the future and having been supremely dissatisfied with any online descriptions I've found in the past, I figure I can stick all the info and links in one place.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Background:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;N-Back is training strategy for increasing one's fluid intelligence. &amp;nbsp;That's basically it. &amp;nbsp;Fluid intelligence has been shown to tie directly to that outdated but romantic idea of IQ and the gist is: &lt;strong&gt;increase&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;fluid intelligence via working memory and get smarter&lt;/strong&gt;. &amp;nbsp;While N-Back has been around since 1958, Jaeggi, one of the major researchers today into the subject, published the widely-cited paper in 2008 titled &quot;Improving Fluid Intelligence with Training on Working Memory&quot; (found &lt;a href='http://1.usa.gov/nJwRMa ' class='offsite-link-inline' target='_blank'&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;) which really started off the wave of testing and N-Back's entrance into popular culture, such as &lt;a href='http://www.wired.com/science/discoveries/news/2008/04/smart_software' class='offsite-link-inline' target='_blank'&gt;this Wired Article&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;nbsp;Since then, a &lt;a href='http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/freeabs_all.jsp?arnumber=5454984' target='_blank'&gt;variety&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a href='http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0160289610001091' target='_blank'&gt;testing&lt;/a&gt; has occurred and in terms of cognitive training, N-Back has proved &lt;a href='http://bit.ly/oOT2Ya' class='offsite-link-inline' target='_blank'&gt;surprisingly robust&lt;/a&gt; in both its short term and long term improvements. &amp;nbsp;Of course, I would be remiss if I didnt mention that there have been criticisms, most of which have been gathered &lt;a href='http://www.gwern.net/DNB%20FAQ#criticism' target='_blank'&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How it works:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The N-Back task falls into two main branches in terms of variation, (1) the type of stimulus and (2) the number of turns one must remember 'back.' &amp;nbsp;The type of stimulus currently varies between audio, spatial, color, and shape (commonly with the first two fulfilling the role). &amp;nbsp;One of the most important elements of the task is maintaining multiple channels of focus by doing two things at once, hence the task is usually referred to as &lt;strong&gt;Dual&lt;/strong&gt; N-Back. &amp;nbsp;The default for most software is Sound and Spatial position (see illustration) but I've found color and spatial to work equally well and much easier to use since it does not require headphones.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class='full-image-float-right ssNonEditable'&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;img src='/images/nback/n_back_test.gif' style='width: 450px;' /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The N in N-Back refers to the number of turns back one must recall. &amp;nbsp;This varies from 1 to as high as around 15. &amp;nbsp;9-back was the highest I've ever heard of anyone reaching, yet the potential is there for far greater numbers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style='font-size: 120%;'&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A D K F &lt;span style='text-decoration: underline;'&gt;K&lt;/span&gt; E F J &lt;span style='text-decoration: underline;'&gt;F&lt;/span&gt; T Y D &lt;span style='text-decoration: underline;'&gt;Y&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style='text-decoration: underline;'&gt;D&lt;/span&gt; W E Q&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So, go out and try some. &amp;nbsp;One of the more interesting elements of N-Back is the near linear improvement from daily use. &amp;nbsp;While there is some plateauing at some of the more difficult numbers (namely 4 and 5-back) improvement appears to be nearly linear; i.e. more NBack == better working memory.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class='full-image-float-left ssNonEditable'&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;img src='http://2.bp.blogspot.com/_SoP7u0HNsxw/Scu_qNosMoI/AAAAAAAAAH0/hDn2LxDJRpc/s400/fig5.png' /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='thumbnail-caption' style='width: 400px;'&gt;via Jaeggi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Back to that longer and more detailed article I mentioned earlier, &lt;a href='http://www.gwern.net/DNB%20FAQ' class='offsite-link-inline' target='_blank'&gt;Gwern's N-Back FAQ&lt;/a&gt; has just about everything else you would be interested in regarding the task. &amp;nbsp;How many a day? What are the limits? Single or Dual NBack? etc.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Personally, I'm quite curious to see how my improvements hold up to Jaeggi's mean data, and while I am a bit less diligent then the peer-reviewed researchers, I'll be happy to post my own improvement after the break come October 1st.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There is a dozen or so options for doing N-Backs on your computer (and even one offline, see FAQ at the bottom). &amp;nbsp;On the desktop there are various programs on every major OS along with a few good browser-based games such as &lt;a href='http://bit.ly/ptpGNK ' class='offsite-link-inline' target='_blank'&gt;SoakYourHead&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;nbsp;I've since posted a review of the various Android options &lt;a href='http://www.limitlesschannels.com/main/2011/8/10/android-n-back-app-comparison.html' target='_blank'&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h2 id='comment'&gt;COMMENT:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AUTHOR: gwern &lt;!--EMAIL: gwern0@gmail.com--&gt; URL: http://www.gwern.net date: 10/02/2011 07:28:17 PM &lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; Since then, a variety of testing has occurred and in terms of cognitive training, N-Back has proved surprisingly robust in both its short term and long term improvements. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;http://www.gwern.net/DNB%20FAQ#criticism&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>NYT Most Looked-up word list</title>
   <link href="http://limitlesschannels.com/language/2011/08/07/nyt-most-looked-up-word-list.html"/>
   <updated>2011-08-07T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://limitlesschannels.com/language/2011/08/07/nyt-most-looked-up-word-list</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;NewYorkTimes.com has a built-in dictionary where readers can instantly look up any word that is used in an article. &amp;nbsp;NYT keeps track of this data and has recently published this year's &quot;Most frequently looked-up words&quot; list.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class='full-image-block ssNonEditable'&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;img src='http://graphics8.nytimes.com/images/2011/07/26/timestopics/26ahead/26ahead-jumbo.jpg' /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;via &lt;a href='http://topics.blogs.nytimes.com/2011/07/26/more-fancy-words/' target='_blank'&gt;NYTimes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, I've been reading Ulysses and picked up half a dozen more, have at thee:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;consubstantial &lt;/strong&gt;- Of the same substance or essence (used esp. of the three persons of the Trinity in Christian theology)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;coign &lt;/strong&gt;- A projecting corner or angle of a wall or building.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;moiety &lt;/strong&gt;- Each of two parts into which a thing is or can be divided.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;postprandial &lt;/strong&gt;- During or relating to the period after dinner or lunch.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;jakes &lt;/strong&gt;- toilet, esp. an outdoor one&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;offal &lt;/strong&gt;- The entrails and internal organs of an animal used as food.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;cad &lt;/strong&gt;- A man who behaves dishonorably, esp. toward a woman.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Just like everything else I try to learn I've compiled these into a convenient deck to be used in Anki, which you can grab &lt;a href='/storage/NYTandUlyssesVocab.anki'&gt;HERE&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;nbsp;I would however recommend that anyone with the time actually enter these manually since the process of inputting them actually does contribute to memorization.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Sinful Depression</title>
   <link href="http://limitlesschannels.com/quotes/2011/08/05/sinful-depression.html"/>
   <updated>2011-08-05T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://limitlesschannels.com/quotes/2011/08/05/sinful-depression</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Thanks to the excellent story-telling podcast &lt;a href='http://themoth.org/' class='offsite-link-inline' title='The Moth weekly Podcast' target='_blank'&gt;The Moth&lt;/a&gt; I was recently reintroduced to one of the seven deadly sins in a way I've never seen or heard previously. &amp;nbsp;One of the less interesting and thus less explored sins is that of Sloth, often translated today as utter laziness. &amp;nbsp;This modern definition however varies quite a bit from the original idea, known as 'Acedia.' &amp;nbsp;&lt;a href='http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Acedia'&gt;Acedia &lt;/a&gt;actually refers to something more along the line of apathy or depression. &amp;nbsp;Thomas Aquinas even had some interesting things to write on that end.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I actually stumbled upon something along a similar vein a while back when I was researching the &quot;unforgivable sin&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style='text-decoration: underline;'&gt;s&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&quot; in the Catholic tradition. &amp;nbsp;For a quick aside I was always curious what that elusive plural included, other than suicide, and after some research concluded that apparently blasphemy against the Holy spirit is one of the only other unforgivable sins, really. &amp;nbsp;Not Jesus, apparently, that's fine, but don't talk about the goddamn holy spirit!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Whoever is not with me is against me, and whoever does not gather with me scatters. And so I tell you, people will be forgiven every sin and blasphemy. But the blasphemy against the Spirit will not be forgiven. Anyone who speaks a word against the&amp;nbsp;Son of Man&amp;nbsp;will be forgiven, but anyone who speaks against the Holy Spirit will not be forgiven, either in this age or in the&amp;nbsp;age to come.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p style='padding-left: 60px;'&gt;~ Matthew 12:30-32&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Even Dostoyevsky had a good bit to say on the relationship between religion and depression. &amp;nbsp;With his exile to Siberia in the latter end of his life, he was supposedly given a copy of the New Testament upon his arrival and with the book as one of his few places of solace, he proceeded to read the text from cover to cover memorizing it and&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;One sees the truth more clearly when one is unhappy, And yet God gives me moments of perfect peace; in such moments I love and believe that I am loved; in such moments I have formulated my creed, wherein all is clear and holy to me. This creed is extremely simply: here it is. I believe that there is nothing lovelier, deeper, more sympathetic, more rational, more manly and more perfect than the Saviour: &lt;em&gt;I say to myself with jealous love that not only is there no one else like Him, but that there could be no one.&amp;rdquo; I confess that one of my coping mechanisms for my depression is that thought &amp;ldquo;One sees the truth more clearly when one is unhappy.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Found with some other writings on Acedia/Depression &lt;a href='http://payingattentiontothesky.com/category/understanding-acediasloth/' class='offsite-link-inline' target='_blank'&gt;here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Language Fact Of The Day 5aug2011</title>
   <link href="http://limitlesschannels.com/language/2011/08/05/language-fact-of-the-day-5aug2011.html"/>
   <updated>2011-08-05T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://limitlesschannels.com/language/2011/08/05/language-fact-of-the-day-5aug2011</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;90% of the population of Paraguay are said to understand the Guarani language.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href='http://www.state.gov/r/pa/ei/bgn/1841.htm'&gt;http://www.state.gov/r/pa/ei/bgn/1841.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Spanish may still be the dominant lang but maybe this will help alleviate the us-vs-them island of Brazilian Portuguese in a sea of Spanish.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>David Foster Wallace's Most Overlooked books of last 50 years</title>
   <link href="http://limitlesschannels.com/links/2011/08/03/david-foster-wallaces-most-overlooked-books.html"/>
   <updated>2011-08-03T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://limitlesschannels.com/links/2011/08/03/david-foster-wallaces-most-overlooked-books</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&quot;Omensetter's Luck&quot;&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;by William H. Gass (1966)&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;Gass' first novel, and his least avant-gardeish, and his best. Basically a religious book. Very sad. Contains the immortal line &quot;The body of Our Saviour shat but Our Saviour shat not.&quot; Bleak but gorgeous, like light through ice.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&quot;Steps&quot;&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;by Jerzy Kosinski (1968)&lt;br /&gt;This won some big prize or other when it first came out, but today nobody seems to remember it. &quot;Steps&quot; gets called a novel but it is really a collection of unbelievably creepy little allegorical tableaux done in a terse elegant voice that's like nothing else anywhere ever. Only Kafka's fragments get anywhere close to where Kosinski goes in this book, which is better than everything else he ever did combined.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&quot;Angels&quot;&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;by Denis Johnson (1983)&lt;br /&gt;This was Johnson's first fiction after the horripilative lyric poetry of &quot;Incognito Lounge.&quot; Even cult fans of &quot;Jesus' Son&quot; often haven't heard of &quot;Angels.&quot; It's sort of &quot;Jesus' Son's&quot; counterpoint, a novel-length odyssey of mopes and scrotes and their brutal redemptions. A totally&amp;nbsp;American&amp;nbsp;book, it's also got great prose, truly great, some of the '80s' best; e.g. lines like &quot;All around them men drank alone, staring out of their faces.&quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&quot;Blood Meridian: Or the Evening Redness in the West&quot;&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;by Cormac McCarthy (1985)&lt;br /&gt;Don't even ask.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&quot;Wittgenstein's Mistress&quot;&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;by David Markson (1988)&lt;br /&gt;&quot;W's M&quot; is a dramatic rendering of what it would be like to live in the sort of universe described by logical atomism. A monologue, formally very odd, mostly one-sentence 6s. Tied with &quot;Omensetter's Luck&quot; for the all-time best U.S. book about human loneliness. These wouldn't constitute ringing endorsements if they didn't happen all to be simultaneously true -- i.e., that a novel this abstract and erudite and avant-garde that could also be so moving makes &quot;Wittgenstein's Mistress&quot; pretty much the high point of experimental fiction in this country.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;via &lt;a href='http://www.salon.com/books/bag/1999/04/12/wallace' class='offsite-link-inline' target='_blank'&gt;Salon&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Quote of the Day 2Aug2011</title>
   <link href="http://limitlesschannels.com/quote/2011/08/02/quote-of-the-day-2aug2011.html"/>
   <updated>2011-08-02T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://limitlesschannels.com/quote/2011/08/02/quote-of-the-day-2aug2011</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&quot;&lt;em&gt;I believe that truth has only one face: that of a violent contradiction&lt;/em&gt;&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;~ Georges Bataille&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Life Update - Blog posts and Cognitive enhancement</title>
   <link href="http://limitlesschannels.com/journal/2011/08/02/life-update-blogposts-and-cognitive-enhancement.html"/>
   <updated>2011-08-02T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://limitlesschannels.com/journal/2011/08/02/life-update-blogposts-and-cognitive-enhancement</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So I've decided to start getting more serious and frequent on this blog. &amp;nbsp;I'll be trying a daily blogging experiment today that I'll be extending for the next two months, or as far as I can actually keep this up. &amp;nbsp;We'll see.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Simultaneously, today is the second day of my two month nootropics/cognitive-training regiment. &amp;nbsp;I've had an interest in smart drugs (often called &lt;a href='http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nootropics' target='_blank'&gt;nootropics&lt;/a&gt;) for quite some time now and while I've played with them in the past, any experiments I've done have lacked in some serious scientific rigor. &amp;nbsp;So, starting yesterday I've mapped out the next two months with twice daily doses of nootropics, once a day general vitamins, and some nice spreadsheet-directed cataloguing. &amp;nbsp;I should be posting some kind of updates in the next few weeks but if not I'll definitely have some nice data by the end of my session to post.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Each day I'll be cataloguing sleep, mood, energy, and exercise on a scale of 0 to 5 as well as participating in 20 daily &lt;a href='http://brainworkshop.sourceforge.net/' target='_blank'&gt;N-Back&lt;/a&gt; sessions and using my long-time friend &lt;a href='http://ichi2.net/anki' target='_blank'&gt;Anki&lt;/a&gt; for spaced-repetition memory testing. &amp;nbsp;N-Back research has pointed to near linear improvement so significant improvement via the noots should increase the slope by N factors, whatever that may be. &amp;nbsp;Color me hopeful but skeptical.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Daily:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Multivitamin&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;B Complex&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DHA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Twice daily:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Piracetam 800mg&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Choline 500mg&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vinpocetine 10mg&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Huperzine 200mcg&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DMAE (and later) ALCAR&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Further information on any of the above can be found below, or go ahead and email/tweet me:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='http://www.gwern.net/DNB%20FAQ' target='_blank'&gt;Excellent lengthy N-Back information page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Regarding Anki, more information can be found on their site or on Wikipedia's &lt;a href='http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Spaced_repetition'&gt;Spaced Repetition article&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and on &lt;a href='http://www.omniglot.com/language/srs.php' target='_blank'&gt;Omniglot's site&lt;/a&gt; which has a nice collection of the different available types.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Legit information on nootropics is widespread and hard to coalesce but &lt;a href='http://www.longecity.org/forum/topic/36691-ten-months-of-research-condensed-a-total-newbies-guide-to-nootropics/' target='_blank'&gt;here's a fairly anecdotal and well-cited forum post&lt;/a&gt; that is honestly one of the better collected information sources I've found. &amp;nbsp;Otherwise, feel free to pick up the classic (and again rather outdated) text &lt;a href='http://www.amazon.com/Smart-Drugs-Nutrients-Intelligence-Neuroscience/dp/0941683249/ref=sr_1_4?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1312331116&amp;amp;sr=8-4' target='_blank'&gt;Smart Drugs by Ward Dean&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h2 id='comment'&gt;COMMENT:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AUTHOR: Dave &amp;lt;!-EMAIL: leecho@gmail.com&amp;gt; DATE: 12/06/2011 06:25:24 PM&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Found this post to be pretty inspiring, mostly cause it seems to be a nice MED for cognitive enhancement. Will you be putting up more info on how it ended up? I got the Ngyuen N-Back app and it is quite nice. Is there any way to get a copy of  the blank spreadsheet you used how you tracked everything? Thank you!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>On Identifying Stress</title>
   <link href="http://limitlesschannels.com/language/2011/07/28/on-identifying-stress.html"/>
   <updated>2011-07-28T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://limitlesschannels.com/language/2011/07/28/on-identifying-stress</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Disclaimer: This is one of my linguistics-heavy posts so unless you are of that prediliction or just genuinely interesting in identifying word stress, go ahead and move on.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Started a thread on Reddit asking about identifying stress, here's some of the better responses:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The trick that I always learned to identify stress was to pronounce the word with incorrect stress. I'm going to avoid using IPA for my example to better illustrate (with caps) what I mean. For &quot;delayed&quot; (assuming my dialectical pronunciation, of course): DEE-laid or dih-LAID.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are the two options for stress, either on the first syllable or the second. For me, the first one sounds like a rapper's name D-laid (lol), whereas the second sounds natural. De&lt;em&gt;layed&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best option when transcribing, however, is to listen to the other para-linguistic attributes of the speech (dynamics, duration of syllable, pitch, vocalic clarity, etc). A vocalic shift often occurs with a shift of stress (ref. PREsent, the gift and preSENT, to display). Some languages have strict rules on where the stress should occur, so that can sometimes help be a guide in determining its location. Finally, keep in mind that stress can also be altered to determine emphasis or can be affected by pauses in speech, so if you can identify those secondary causes, it might help you in figuring out the exact location of the stress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;and another one:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you're trying to figure out the stress of just a single word, try saying the word naturally, like you would in a sentence or normal discourse. If you enunciate all the syllables in the word, then of course that makes it more difficult. English has vowel reduction--i.e. on unstressed syllables, the vowel tends to get reduced to a schwa. So &lt;strong&gt;listen for schwas, that'll indicate it's an unstressed syllable&lt;/strong&gt;. In my dialect, I would&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;never&lt;/em&gt;&amp;nbsp;say [di.lejd] (unless I'm really enunciating), but rather [d.lejd]. So the stress is on the second syllable the way I say it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stressed syllables are also longer in duration and louder.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;and another one, perhaps the simplest:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Try humming, marching or clapping your hands as you pronounce the words. You can also say them very loud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Language Infodump 28jul2011</title>
   <link href="http://limitlesschannels.com/language/2011/07/28/language-infodump-28jul2011.html"/>
   <updated>2011-07-28T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://limitlesschannels.com/language/2011/07/28/language-infodump-28jul2011</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Deconcrete has a piece on &lt;a href='http://www.deconcrete.org/2011/07/26/landscape-generated-languages/' target='_blank'&gt;Landscape-Generated Languages&lt;/a&gt;, such as the whistle-speech of the Amazonian basin tribe the Kickapoo. &amp;nbsp;Also some cool video and audio links.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;A while back Google Translate added a text-to-speech transcription feature that some have turned into a killer beatbox machine, more on &lt;a href='http://googletranslate.blogspot.com/2011/05/google-translate-remix.html' target='_blank'&gt;Google Translate's own blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Germany's recent campaign to promote German learning among immigrant populations has some clever and aggressive marketing backing the effort. &amp;nbsp;Langauge on the Move has a piece on the new &lt;a href='http://www.languageonthemove.com/language-migration-social-justice/the-cult-of-personal-responsibility' target='_blank'&gt;Cult of Personal Responsibility&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;New York Times just posted their &lt;a href='http://topics.blogs.nytimes.com/2011/07/26/more-fancy-words/' target='_blank'&gt;2011 list of the most looked-up words&lt;/a&gt; on NYTimes.com, how many do you know?&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>How Noun and Verb shortages could predict the next Stock Market Crash</title>
   <link href="http://limitlesschannels.com/language/2011/07/19/how-noun-and-verb-shortages-could-predict-the-next-stock-market-crash.html"/>
   <updated>2011-07-19T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://limitlesschannels.com/language/2011/07/19/how-noun-and-verb-shortages-could-predict-the-next-stock-market-crash</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Nice.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;By plotting the distributions of words used in financial articles published online between 2006 and 2010 into a computer model, we were able to identify what we call 'verb convergence' and 'noun convergence &amp;mdash; where the language used by financial journalists shows converging agreement. Our study shows that reporters converge on the same language &amp;mdash; 'stocks rose again', 'scaled new heights', or 'soared' &amp;mdash; as their commentaries became more uniformly positive in the lead up to the 2007 crash. They also appear to refer to a smaller-than-usual set of market events &amp;mdash; presumably because of an increased fixation on a small number of rapidly rising stocks.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='http://ijcai.org/papers11/Papers/IJCAI11-374.pdf' target='_blank'&gt;PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;(headline and referal via io9)&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Why linguists should study math (and when they shouldn't use it)</title>
   <link href="http://limitlesschannels.com/language/2011/07/09/why-linguists-should-study-math-and-when-they-shouldnt-use-it.html"/>
   <updated>2011-07-09T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://limitlesschannels.com/language/2011/07/09/why-linguists-should-study-math-and-when-they-shouldnt-use-it</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I found in the archives of&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href='http://thelousylinguist.blogspot.com/' class='offsite-link-inline' target='_blank'&gt;The Lousy Linguistic&lt;/a&gt; blog &lt;a href='http://thelousylinguist.blogspot.com/2010/01/why-linguists-should-study-math.html' target='_blank'&gt;a great post on the importance of studying mathematics, &lt;/a&gt;specifically logic and statistics, in linguistics. &amp;nbsp;With the recent rise in popularity in such fields as psycholinguistics or Natural Language Processing it has indeed become increasingly important but even such basics as transformational grammar and semantic analysis have been enhanced through mathematical thinking.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Linguists should study math* because&lt;/strong&gt;...&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style='padding-left: 30px;'&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a name='more' /&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul style='padding-left: 30px;'&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Math is a tool that helps you.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;It's not that hard.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Math is good training for the mind.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Math is the future.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;You will be left behind without it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;You will be a better linguist.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;An important caveat and one of Chris' excellent points in the post is the importance but not over-importance of utilizing mathematical analysis within linguistics. &amp;nbsp;Yes, it is extremely helpful and important for all the listed reasons but the goal is linguistic analysis-- not mathematical-- and to rely too heavily on math will lead to inaccurate and bad language work.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Why? &amp;nbsp;Because language is based on human thought and as humans we are not rational creatures. &amp;nbsp;We try to be, and it is a worthy pursuit, but at best one is imposing a rational framework on an irrational system.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Actually, in an older separate post he writes on this very point, although in a somewhat different context on his &lt;a href='http://thelousylinguist.blogspot.com/2007/12/linguists-vs-economists.html'&gt;Linguists versus Economists&lt;/a&gt; piece:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;&lt;em&gt;Part of the difference is probably due to the fact that economists work under the assumption that economic decisions are conscious and rational while linguists work under the assumption that linguistic decisions are automatic or unconscious&lt;/em&gt;&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;So.. mathematics, good, but handle with care or you could be one of those &lt;a href='http://www.businessweek.com/lifestyle/content/healthday/651912.html'&gt;anthropologists&lt;/a&gt;/biologists/mathematicians/game theorists who pop up every other week with a new &quot;I just spent 10 minutes figuring out how language works&quot; theory. &amp;nbsp;&lt;a href='http://xkcd.com/793/' target='_blank'&gt;Relevant&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Google Research Maps Cross Linguistic Links On The Web</title>
   <link href="http://limitlesschannels.com/language/2011/07/09/google-research-maps-cross-linguistic-links-on-the-web.html"/>
   <updated>2011-07-09T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://limitlesschannels.com/language/2011/07/09/google-research-maps-cross-linguistic-links-on-the-web</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class='full-image-block ssNonEditable'&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;img src='/storage/PR_mapped.png' /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Google Research blog (which until this post I never knew actually existed) just posted some cool data (with chart porn!) on cross-language linkage throughout the web. &amp;nbsp;High linguistic correlations between certain languages across sites mirrors a surprisingly similar geographic distributions, which depending on who you are may or may not have been obvious (I'm undecided myself).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Disregarding the world language of English the languages appear to link across such alliances as former soviet republics and &amp;nbsp;the data even demonstrate geographic isolationist and introverted cultures such as the surprisingly large lack of English among Chinese and Japanese sites.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;more &lt;a href='http://googleresearch.blogspot.com/2011/07/languages-of-world-wide-web.html' class='offsite-link-inline' target='_blank'&gt;HERE&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>1786 Ponderings On Cats</title>
   <link href="http://limitlesschannels.com/2011/07/07/1786-ponderings-on-cats.html"/>
   <updated>2011-07-07T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://limitlesschannels.com/2011/07/07/1786-ponderings-on-cats</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;layout: post title: 1768 Ponderings on Cats date: 2011-07-07 category: main tags: - cats&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id='description_an_excerpt_from_18th_century_encyclopedia_on_cats'&gt;description: An excerpt from 18th century Encyclopedia on cats&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Short excerpt from the absurd piece filed under &quot;Cat&quot; for the first edition of the Encyclopedia Britannica, back in 1768 when it was a mere three volumes with three contributors:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style='padding-left: 30px;'&gt;&lt;em&gt;Of all domestic animals, the character of the cat is the most equivocal and suspicious. &amp;nbsp;He is kept, not for any amiable qualities, but purely with a view to banish rats, mice and other noxious animals from our houses... Constantly bent upon theft and rapine, they are full of cunning and dissimulation; they conceal all their designs; seize every opportunity of doing mischief, and then fly from punishment... In a word, the cat is totally destitute of friendship.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, they are considered &quot;overly amorous&quot; (i.e. horny) and while pretending to sleep &quot;in reality they are meditating mischief.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;via A.J. Jacobs' book &quot;The Know-It-All&quot;&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Language Infodump 5jul2011</title>
   <link href="http://limitlesschannels.com/language/2011/07/05/language-infodump-5jul2011.html"/>
   <updated>2011-07-05T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://limitlesschannels.com/language/2011/07/05/language-infodump-5jul2011</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Contrary to popular opinion,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href='http://www.cbsnews.com/8301-504763_162-20076886-10391704.html' target='_blank'&gt;new Australian study&lt;/a&gt; shows no lasting effect in the 1 in 10 children who learn to talk later. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Over on the Guardian &lt;a href='http://www.guardian.co.uk/education/2011/jul/05/teaching-english-fractal-grammar-claypole' target='_blank'&gt;Bringing Chaos theory to English Language Teaching&lt;/a&gt; discusses application in light of the constant issues involved in mapping spoken language and the organic growth of grammatical rules.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nice video floating around on &lt;a href='http://digg.com/news/lifestyle/the_history_of_the_english_language_in_10_minutes' target='_blank'&gt;History of the English Language in 10 minutes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The always excellent Neuroskeptic has &lt;a href='http://neuroskeptic.blogspot.com/2011/06/machine-readable-psychiatry.html' target='_blank'&gt;a piece&lt;/a&gt; on using Natural Language Processing (the other NLP) for machine-readable psychiatry diagnosis.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Garden Path Sentences</title>
   <link href="http://limitlesschannels.com/language/2011/07/03/garden-path-sentences.html"/>
   <updated>2011-07-03T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://limitlesschannels.com/language/2011/07/03/garden-path-sentences</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Garden Path Sentences are some of the more interesting cognitive linguistic tools that give us some clever insight into how our minds process syntax. A Garden Path sentence involves an initial (incorrect) reading of the phrase and a subsequent rereading for the correct meaning. The basic idea is that we process sentences on the fly and bi-directionally. Without delving too deeply into models of visual word processing and how we read, there are several fascinating insights into the way this works, but for brevity sake I'll just give some examples. The sentences are first read through sequentially from left to right but upon reaching the end of the phrase in confusion, the eyes of the reader will jump back and forth in a reinterpretation of the sentence to find the true meaning.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Before reading the intepretations try and figure out the meaning of the sentences yourself:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&quot;The old man the boat.&quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Intepretation One: &lt;span onmouseover='this.style.color=&amp;apos;#FFF&amp;apos;;' onmouseout='this.style.color=this.style.backgroundColor=&amp;apos;#000&amp;apos;;' style='background-color: #000; color: #000;'&gt;&quot;&lt;em&gt;[The old man]&lt;span style='vertical-align: sub;'&gt;NP&lt;/span&gt; [the boat]&lt;span style='vertical-align: sub;'&gt;NP&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.&quot; two sequential noun phrases (NPs) with no perceivable verb.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Interpretation Two (post restructuring): &lt;span onmouseover='this.style.color=&amp;apos;#FFF&amp;apos;;' onmouseout='this.style.color=this.style.backgroundColor=&amp;apos;#000&amp;apos;;' style='background-color: #000; color: #000;'&gt;&quot;&lt;em&gt;[The old]&lt;span style='vertical-align: sub;'&gt;NP&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;[man]&lt;span style='vertical-align: sub;'&gt;VERB&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;[the boat]&lt;span style='vertical-align: sub;'&gt;NP.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&quot; &amp;nbsp;After the first reading &quot;man&quot; is revealed to be the verb, not part of the subject noun phrase.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style='vertical-align: sub;'&gt;Or my favorite and perhaps the best well-known:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style='vertical-align: sub;'&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;nbsp;&quot;The horse raced past the barn fell&quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Interpretation One: &lt;span onmouseover='this.style.color=&amp;apos;#FFF&amp;apos;;' onmouseout='this.style.color=this.style.backgroundColor=&amp;apos;#000&amp;apos;;' style='background-color: #000; color: #000;'&gt;&quot;&lt;em&gt;[The horse]&lt;span style='vertical-align: sub;'&gt;NP&lt;/span&gt; [raced]&lt;span style='vertical-align: sub;'&gt;V&lt;/span&gt; [past]&lt;span style='vertical-align: sub;'&gt;AD&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style='vertical-align: sub;'&gt;V&lt;/span&gt; [the barn]&lt;span style='vertical-align: sub;'&gt;NP&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;[fell]&lt;span style='vertical-align: sub;'&gt;???&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&quot; Here the reader will first read it as a complete sentence with a stranded verb &quot;fell.&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Interpretation Two (post restructuring): &lt;span onmouseover='this.style.color=&amp;apos;#FFF&amp;apos;;' onmouseout='this.style.color=this.style.backgroundColor=&amp;apos;#000&amp;apos;;' style='background-color: #000; color: #000;'&gt;&quot;&lt;em&gt;[The horse raced past the barn]&lt;span style='vertical-align: sub;'&gt;NP&lt;/span&gt; [fell]&lt;span style='vertical-align: sub;'&gt;VERB&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&quot; Where everything but the verb &quot;fell&quot; is part of the subject noun phrase. &amp;nbsp;In this case the horse &lt;strong&gt;is being raced&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style='vertical-align: sub;'&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; Here, while both are correct a clarification for the sentences ambiguity could be rephrasing the sentence as &quot;The horse &lt;strong&gt;that was &lt;/strong&gt;raced past the barn fell&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;p style='vertical-align: sub;'&gt;Here's a short Youtube video demonstrating saccades in reading:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; http://www.youtube.com/embed/VFIZDZwdf-0?rel=0 &lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Top Blogs</title>
   <link href="http://limitlesschannels.com/2011/04/19/top-blogs.html"/>
   <updated>2011-04-19T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://limitlesschannels.com/2011/04/19/top-blogs</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;(Update since has just been merged into sidebar links page)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I tend to prefer some kind of longform to my blogs; linkdumps have their place (that's what Twitter is for) but whenever I can I try and follow a fair amount of original-content generators. &amp;nbsp;In that regard, here are some of my absolute favorites:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;A recent discovery, no idea who this is but its a brilliant mixture of in-depth film reviews, linguistic research, and a bit of everything.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href='http://www.mstrmnd.com/log/' target='_blank'&gt;www.mstrmnd.com/log/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Joan McNeill's thought experiment. &amp;nbsp;Joanne has consistently had such an impressive and diverse social link I'm always surprised by the depth and variety across her blog, also for the Google Reader users, she is consistently sharing new/interesting stuff.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href='http://www.tomorrowmuseum.com' target='_blank'&gt;www.tomorrowmuseum.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Neuroscience and mindhacks, fantastic stuff.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href='http://www.mindhacks.com' target='_blank'&gt;www.mindhacks.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Klint Finley's excellent technology, weird science, and the occult blog. &amp;nbsp;It's been around for a while and while this may be more my niche than most, he has consistently put out good content for ages&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href='http://www.technoccult.com' target='_blank'&gt;www.technoccult.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Rationality community blog, nuff said.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href='http://www.lesswrong.com' target='_blank'&gt;www.lesswrong.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Language Infodump 2feb2011</title>
   <link href="http://limitlesschannels.com/language/2011/02/02/language-infodump-2feb2011.html"/>
   <updated>2011-02-02T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>http://limitlesschannels.com/language/2011/02/02/language-infodump-2feb2011</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Looks like a sad day for language learners across the web, Smart.fm returns to its iKnow roots but this time &lt;a href='http://www.tofugu.com/2011/01/26/smartfm-closing-down/'&gt;throws up a big ol' paywall&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Some new info over on ionpsych: &lt;a href='http://www.ionpsych.com/2011/02/01/effortless-language-learning-not-just-for-kids/'&gt;Effortless Language Learning: not just for kids&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Don't get tricked with the SEO-worthy catchy title, &amp;nbsp;but some &lt;a href='http://thelousylinguist.blogspot.com/2011/01/linguistics-of-heaven-and-hell.html'&gt;nice reading over on Lousy Linguist&lt;/a&gt; about measuring Voice Onset Time in pop culture's &quot;Big Brother&quot; to derive a caste system.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;While I personally think Quora is completely useless, maybe Babylon's attempt at making themselves and their 72 million members the &quot;&lt;a href='http://techcrunch.com/2011/01/26/babylon-aims-to-build-a-quora-for-linguistics-off-its-72-million-members/'&gt;Quora of Linguistics&lt;/a&gt;&quot; should pan out into sheer online Web 3.0 awesomeness.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Finally, Radiolab had a &lt;a href='http://www.radiolab.org/2010/oct/08/'&gt;great episode&lt;/a&gt; a while back on what makes cities cities. &amp;nbsp;The crazy work they do over at the world-reknown Sante Fe Institute in emergent behavior and complexity gets some application in deriving city size and average number of libraries from walking speed and rate of speech.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Language Infodump 14jan2011</title>
   <link href="http://limitlesschannels.com/language/2011/01/14/language-infodump-14jan2011.html"/>
   <updated>2011-01-14T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>http://limitlesschannels.com/language/2011/01/14/language-infodump-14jan2011</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8CBsxCUhNu0'&gt;Nice YouTube link&lt;/a&gt; on the Spike Jonze-directed music video for The Pharcyde's &quot;Drop&quot; and their linguist's work on teaching the rap backwards.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Yet another prescriptive language Nazi rant &lt;a href='http://www.slate.com/id/2281146/'&gt;over on Slate&lt;/a&gt; about hatred for the double-space trend between sentences. &amp;nbsp;Personally, I've always been a fan.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Keith over on his Extreme Language Learning blog has &lt;a href='http://natural-language-acquisition.blogspot.com/2011/01/two-thousand-hours.html'&gt;just completed his 2000 hours of silence project&lt;/a&gt;, watching 2000 hours of Chinese television with zero supplementary grammar or language books. &amp;nbsp;Should be interesting to see how he finally does when he gets around to testing his capability with a speaker.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href='http://www.thenounproject.com/'&gt;The Noun Project&lt;/a&gt; is an interesting new language project to create a universal (western-centric, clearly) iconography.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Earlier this week the GOP had &lt;a href='http://www.tcdailyplanet.net/news/2011/01/12/gop-introduces-bill-make-english-minnesota%E2%80%99s-official-language'&gt;introduced a new bill&lt;/a&gt; to make English the official language of Minnesota.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Layman's Tea Breakdown</title>
   <link href="http://limitlesschannels.com/main/2010/11/07/Laymans-tea-breakdown.html"/>
   <updated>2010-11-07T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://limitlesschannels.com/main/2010/11/07/Laymans-tea-breakdown</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Been doing some research on tea lately. This is a super-basic breakdown to help someone from being totally overwhelmed with a tea menu. Here's a quick list of the different types, caffeine content, etc. There are 2real types of Tea; those from the Camellia Sinensis plant and &quot;Herbal.&quot; Camellia Sinensis is the real tea-tree type, while herbal is the catch all for everything we've come to associate with tea, but really is just a bunch of herbs to be drunk together. Remind me to throw together a post on folk taxonomies in the future to go further into this catch-all business.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Quick brewing note: Excessively hot water causes release of tannin, i.e. you'll be drinking bitter tea. Water should not be boiling when added, but just under. Steeping time should be around 3o seconds to 3 minutes.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Camellia Sinensis&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Green Tea&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Green tea is as basic as you can get, widespread usage originated from China but has since spread to being grown all throughout Asia and throughout the world. Green tea is straight off the plant, &lt;strong&gt;unoxidized &lt;/strong&gt;and dried with minimal processing.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	&lt;li&gt;Caffeine: 20mg (range :15-30)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h4&gt;White Tea&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;br /&gt;White tea is a somewhat younger version of green tea. White tea is picked before the buds have fully flowered (i.e. have little white hairs still on them, hence the name). The &lt;strong&gt;least caffeinated&lt;/strong&gt; of any natural tea, due to its young age. Also &lt;strong&gt;unoxidized with minimal processing.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	&lt;li&gt;Caffeine: 15mg (range: 6-25)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Black Tea&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Black tea is &lt;strong&gt;fully oxidized, giving it a stronger flavor and more caffeine&lt;/strong&gt;. The process grants black tea a longer shelf-life, so it could originally be transported to Europe and survive the trip from Asia with more flavor and plenty of caffeine. Still made with Camellia Sinensis but occasionally leaves from the Assamese variety.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;br /&gt;	&lt;li&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Caffeine: 40mg (range: 40-60)&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Oolong Tea&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Oolong tea is traditionally a Chinese tea, partially oxidized and therefore halfway between a green and a black. &lt;strong&gt;Oxidation is between 10 to 70%&lt;/strong&gt;. This is the most popular tea served in Chinese restaurants.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Herbal&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;br /&gt;There are way, way too many varieties to list here since this is basically a made-up category but I'll cover just two of the most popular.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Yerba Mate&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Mate is made from the Ilex Paraguarensis plant. It is harvested heavily throughout South America and extremely popular throughout Argentina and Brazil. Usually drunk out of a gourd, some like to add some lemon to it, where it earned the nickname &quot;terere&quot; [TEH-REH-RAY, trilling each &quot;R&quot;]. Mate has been believed to have a chemical called Mateine in it, as an alternative to caffeine but recent research and really shown the two to be more or lesssynonymous.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Rooibos Tea&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Rooibos Tea (aka &quot;Red Tea&quot;) is made from Aspalathus Linearis, a red bush plant popular in South Africa. The plant has a &lt;strong&gt;low tannin&lt;/strong&gt; concentration and &lt;strong&gt;no caffeine&lt;/strong&gt;, making it a nice alternative to teas of the Camellia family.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Remember Everything Forever</title>
   <link href="http://limitlesschannels.com/memory/2010/10/22/remember-everything-forever.html"/>
   <updated>2010-10-22T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://limitlesschannels.com/memory/2010/10/22/remember-everything-forever</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is the first in a series of memory posts.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Phonetic System, Peg System, Loci System and Memory Palace.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Highlights from Pandora Town Hall</title>
   <link href="http://limitlesschannels.com/notes/2010/10/22/Highlights-from-the-pandora-townhall.html"/>
   <updated>2010-10-22T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://limitlesschannels.com/notes/2010/10/22/Highlights-from-the-pandora-townhall</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I attended the &amp;#8220;Pandora Town Hall&amp;#8221; meeting tonight where Tim (founder of Pandora.com) spoke at Weiden+Kennedy advertising firm. The talk was an illuminating look into the history of the company, its founding and inevitable financial issues, and most interestingly the Music Genome Project powering the site. The meet-ups are apparently something Tim has been doing since the founding of the site in 2005 where he travels around to get real input from the genuine site users.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The idea of Pandora came about sometime around January of 2000 and finally solidified into the free service Pandora.com in November of 2005. Before that the site was a subscription service with the first 10 hours free then a $3 a month credit card fee.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Apparently the site designer used to work at a children&amp;#8217;s museum, hence the simplicity of design.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;As Tim says &amp;#8220;thumbing is kind of an art.&amp;#8221; and users LOVE to thumb. Some 2 billion thumbs were processed in 2010 alone.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How about that Music Genome Project? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;400 genes make up the genome for song sequencing by Pandora&amp;#8217;s analysts. Pandora employs some 25 musicians who simply sit and listen to music all day scoring songs on headphones. Every single song (about 80,000 within the system now) is done manually, since computers cannot do the quality job a true human can. A 4-minute pop song takes about 15 minutes to map, and a symphony can take an hour and a half. The team seems to map out about 10,000 songs a month this way.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Tempo is the most defining feature of the genome map.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Analysts must go through 100 hours of training before they can map pop/rock songs. After that, there is another test and tier for jazz mapping, and then even a third for the elusive classical music mappers.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Only 10% of songs need to be mapped twice. If need be, with additional mapping over 90% are within a couple points of each other.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How are which songs to be added chosen?&lt;/strong&gt; Every missed search is tracked data to give the analysts heads-up on what music to add next.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Metadata?&lt;/strong&gt; The only metadata used in mapping is year song was released. The Pandora team is actually pretty damn religious about user privacy and stores next to nothing on user-identifiable data.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What about artist royalties?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Artists are paid 2 cents an hour (which seriously adds up given the amount of music constantly streaming (that&amp;#8217;s some 65 million users in the U.S. alone). Pandora pulled in $500 million revenue last year with 60% paid to artists as performance and publishing fees.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tips:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If you like a certain band with a long, varying career and only really like one genre of their stuff, Tim recommended launching the station by a specific song, rather than the artist. Due to the intricacies of the genome, it will give you a more accurate reading by the style of the song over the artist.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Bookmarking and Skipping are neutral features on Pandora that do not affect likes/dislikes.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Songs are played in 3 or 4 song sets, if you&amp;#8217;re curious about stylization patterns.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 
</feed>
